Witness the return of Jigsaw.
Saw X is a horror, mystery film directed by Kevin Greutert.
Between the events of 'Saw' and 'Saw II', a sick and desperate John Kramer travels to Mexico for a risky and experimental medical procedure
in hopes of a miracle cure for his cancer, only to discover the entire operation is a scam to defraud the most vulnerable.
Armed with a newfound purpose, the infamous serial killer returns to his work, turning the tables on the
con artists in his signature visceral way through devious, deranged, and ingenious traps.
John Kramer, played by Tobin Bell.
Amanda Young, played by Shawnee Smith.
Cecilia Pederson, played by Synnøve Macody Lund.
Parker Sears, played by Steven Brand.
Gabriela, played by Renata Vaca.
Diego, played by Joshua Okamoto.
Saw X is a 2023 American horror film directed and edited by Kevin
Greutert, and written by Peter Goldfinger and Josh Stolberg.
It is the tenth installment in the Saw film series, following Spiral (2021) and stars Tobin Bell and Shawnee Smith, who reprise
their roles from the previous films, alongside Synnøve Macody Lund, Steven Brand, Renata Vaca, and Michael Beach.
Set between the events of Saw (2004) and Saw II (2005), the film sees John Kramer (Bell)
travelling to Mexico in hopes that an experimental procedure may cure his terminal cancer.
John later discovers that the operation is a scam, prompting him to kidnap those responsible and subject them to
his trademark death traps as retribution, with Amanda Young (Smith) acting as his accomplice.
A tenth installment was reported to be in development with Twisted Pictures in April 2021, when Stolberg and Goldfinger,
writers for the previous two entries of the series, announced that they had completed the script in December 2021.
Greutert, who had directed two other installments of the series and
edited six, was also confirmed as the film's director.
Filming took place between October 2022 and February 2023 in Mexico City.
Saw X was theatrically released by Lionsgate Films on September 29, 2023.
It grossed $125 million worldwide and received generally positive
reviews from critics, making it the best-reviewed Saw film.
Following a tumultuous pre-production regarding a follow-up to Saw X, Blumhouse Productions bought out Twisted Pictures' stake in the franchise in
June 2025, with Lionsgate retaining substantial ownership, making this film the last Saw film to be produced by Twisted Pictures.
The film explores themes of mexico, mexico city, mexico, sadism, riddle, gore.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.